Hi I'm James Dix from reptile rescue service in Salt Lake City, Utah.
And we are discussing how to take care of your painted turtle or either an aquatic turtle or painted turtle.
Pretty much the same thing just a different species.
This particular one here is an Asian leaf turtle but you would give them a habitat that would be in your house a twenty gallon tank filtration system.
Make sure that you have a log or a rock that they can climb up out of the water cause they do like to Basque under a heat lamp.
You need to put in a zoom in heat lamp depending on what size tank would be the wattage they can tell you how deep your tank is what you would need at the pet store.
Most of the time it's seventy five watt and up.
It's very critical that you keep their water clean, that you have a good filtration pump because if you don't the pump will plug up and they can get fungus and other diseases.
It's also very important to let your children know or whoever is handling the turtle that always wash your hands afterwards cause aquatic turtles carry a lot of pin worms and salmonella.
So make sure that you do follow these procedures and these little tips on keeping your hands clean and you'll have a healthy turtle and also nobody will catch anything from your turtle.